gatestoneinstitute.org 2019-12-30

# Privacy and Cookies Policy :: Gatestone Institute

This is the Privacy and Cookies Policy for the website hosted at [gatestoneinstitute.org](https://www.gatestoneinstitute.org/) (" **we** ", " **us** " and " **our site** "). The site is operated by or on behalf of Gatestone Institute. We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our Terms of Use (<https://www.gatestoneinstitute.org/terms-of-use/>) and any other documents referred to on it) sets out:

  * Information we collect about you
  * Cookies and other technologies
  * How we use your information
  * Our promotional updates and communications
  * Who we give your information to
  * Where we store your information
  * Public forums
  * How we protect your information
  * How long we keep your information
  * Your rights
  * Changes to this policy
  * Contact us

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

By accepting our services you acknowledge you have read and understood this privacy policy.

For the purposes of European Economic Area data protection law, (the " **Data Protection Law** "), the data controller is: Gatestone Institute of 14 E. 60th Street, New York, NY 10022, USA.

**_Information we collect about you_**

We will collect and process the following personal data from you:

**Information you give us**

This is information about you that you give us directly when you interact with us.

This is information about you that you give us by filling in forms on our site or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our service, search for a product, place an order on site, participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on or via our site, enter a competition, promotion or survey, submit a query, and when you report a problem with our site. 

The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information, personal description and photograph, login and password details.

**Information we collect about you from your use of our site:** We will automatically collect information from you each time you visit our site. This includes:

  * Technical information
  * Information about your visit

  * Technical information may include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; 

  * Information about your visit may include the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page, and any phone number used to call our customer service number or social media handle used to connect with our customer service team.

**Information we receive from other sources.** This is information we receive about you:

  * If you use any of the other websites or apps we operate or the other services we provide.
  * From third parties we work closely with.

In this case we will have informed you [via this policy] when we collected that data if we intend to share your data internally and combine it with data collected on this site. We will also have told you for what purpose we will share and combine your data. 

We are working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, and search information providers). We will notify you when we receive information about you from them and the purposes for which we intend to use that information.

**_Cookies and other technologies_**

Our site uses cookies to collect and store certain information. These typically involve pieces of information or code that a website transfers to or accesses from your computer hard drive or mobile device to store and sometimes track information about you. Cookies and similar technologies enable you to be remembered when using that computer or device to interact with websites and online services and can be used to manage a range of features and content as well as storing searches and presenting personalized content.

Our site uses cookies and similar technologies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site and also allows us to improve our site.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies and similar technologies, but if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that and your help screen or manual will tell you how to do this. We also give you information below about how to disable cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of our website if you do so.

A number of cookies and similar technologies we use last only for the duration of your web or app session and expire when you close your browser. Others are used to remember you when you return to the site and will last for longer.

We use these cookies and other technologies on the basis that they are necessary for the performance of a contract with you, or because using them is in our legitimate interests (where we have considered that these are not overridden by your rights), and, in some cases, where required by law, where you have consented to their use.

We use the following types of cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary** cookies **.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website and under our terms with you. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.

  * **Analytical/performance** cookies **.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us for our legitimate interests of improving the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

  * **Functionality** cookies **.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us, subject to your choices and preferences, to personalise our content, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

  * **Targeting** cookies **.** These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information subject to your choices and preferences to make our website/App and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. **We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.**

We may also work with advertising networks that gather information about the content on our website you visit and on information on other websites and services you visit. This may result in you seeing advertisements on our site or our advertisements when you visit other websites and services of third parties. For more information about how to turn this feature off see below or visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

**Disabling cookies**

The effect of disabling cookies depends on which cookies you disable but, in general, the website may not operate properly if all cookies are switched off. If you only disable third party cookies, you will not be prevented from making purchases on our site. If you disable all cookies, you will be unable to complete a purchase on our site.

If you want to disable cookies on our site, you need to change your website browser settings to reject cookies. How you can do this will depend on the browser you use. Further details on how to disable cookies for the most popular browsers are set out below:

**For Microsoft Internet Explorer:**

1\. Choose the menu "tools" then "Internet Options"  
2\. Click on the "privacy" tab  
3\. Select the setting the appropriate setting

**For Google Chrome:**

1\. Choose Settings then Advanced  
2\. Under "Privacy and security," click "Content settings".  
3\. Click "Cookies"

**For Safari:**

1\. Choose Preferences then Privacy  
2\. Click on "Remove all Website Data"

**For Mozilla Firefox:**

1\. Choose the menu "tools" then "Options"  
2\. Click on the icon "privacy"  
3\. Find the menu "cookie" and select the relevant options

**For Opera 6.0 and further:**

1\. Choose the menu Files then "Preferences"  
2\. Privacy

Where you have not set your permissions, we may also separately prompt you regarding our use of cookies on the Site.

Except for essential cookies, all cookies used on our site will expire after no later than 2 years after they have been placed.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them:

| 

**Cookie**

| 

**Purpose and lawful basis**  
  
---|---  
  
sub_promo_status

sub_promo_updated

| 

These cookies track whether a visitor has been are served the subscription promotion popup, and whether the visitor responded to it by signing up. They also prevent users from getting the subscription popups again if they've already subscribed, or if not, from getting it too often.  
  
donation_promo_status

donation_promo_updated

| 

These cookies track whether a visitor has been are served the donation promotional popup, and whether the visitor responded to it by visiting the donation page and/or submitting the donation form. They also prevent users from getting the popups again if they're already donated, or if not, from getting it too often.  
  
c_ar

| 

This cookie tracks whether a visitor arrived on the Site from a specific external ad campaign or promotional campaign, and possibly signed up to the mailing list.  
  
PHP session managament

| 

PHP sessions expire automatically when the visitor's browser is closed or within a couple of hours if the browser stays open.  
  
Google Analytics

| 

This provides Site analytics in respect of how the Site is used by users. For more information about how Google collects and use personal data please see: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html>  
  
AddThis

| 

This allows third parties to place cookies to allow you to share content through social media. For more information about how AddThis collects and uses personal data please see: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>  
  
Taboola

| 

Taboola is a native advertising company delivering personalised advertising. For more information about this Taboola and this cookie please see: www <https://www.taboola.com/cookie-policy>  
  
**_How we use your information_**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

**Information you give to us:**

We will use this information to:

  * Take steps in order to enter into any contract or carry out our obligations arising from any contract entered into between you and us including:

    * administering your account with us;
    * notifying you about changes to our service.
  * Provide you with information about our goods or services we feel may interest you, if you have given your consent to receiving marketing material from us at the point we collected your information, where required by law or otherwise in our legitimate interests provided these interests do not override your right to object to such communications. See 'Our promotional updates and communications'.

  * Ensure in our legitimate interests that:

    * content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
    * we provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us.

**Information we collect about you from your use of our site**

We will use this information in our legitimate interests, where we have considered these are not overridden by your rights:

  * To administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes.
  * To keep our site safe and secure.
  * For measuring or understanding the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you.
  * To improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.

**Information we receive from other sources**

We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you in our legitimate interests (where we have considered that these are not overridden by your rights). We will use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

**_Our promotional updates and communications_**

Where permitted in our legitimate interest or with your prior consent where required by law, we will use your personal information for marketing analysis and to provide you with promotional update communications by email about our services.

You can object to further marketing at any time by checking and updating your contact details within your account, or selecting the "unsubscribe" link at the end of all our marketing and promotional update communications to you, or by sending us an email to [info@gatestoneinstitute.org](mailto:info@gatestoneinstitute.org).

**_Who we give your information to_**

We may give your information to:

  * Any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, who support our processing of personal data under this policy.
  * Selected third parties.

Our selected third parties may include:

  * Organizations who process your personal data on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions and the Data Protection Law. This includes in supporting the services we offer through the site in particular those providing website and data hosting services, providing fulfilment services, distributing any communications we send, supporting or updating marketing lists, facilitating feedback on our services and providing IT support services from time to time. These organizations (which may include third party suppliers, agents, sub-contractors and/or other companies in our group) will only use your information to the extent necessary to perform their support functions.

  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimization of our site and subject to the cookie section of this policy (this will not identify you as an individual).

  * We will disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets subject to the terms of this privacy policy.

  * If Gatestone Institute or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of supply terms and other agreements with you; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Gatestone Institute, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction and to prevent cybercrime.

**_Where we store your information_**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** ") that may not be subject to equivalent Data Protection Law.

Where your information is transferred outside the EEA, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is subject to appropriate safeguards, such as relying on a recognized legal adequacy mechanism, and that it is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

We may transfer your personal information outside the EEA:

  * In order to store it.
  * In order to enable us to provide goods or services to you and fulfil our contract with you. This includes order fulfilment, processing of payment details, and the provision of support services.
  * Where we are legally required to do so.
  * In order to facilitate the operation of our group of businesses, where it is in our legitimate interests and we have concluded these are not overridden by your rights.

**Public forums**

The site may, from time to time, make chat rooms, message boards, news groups and/or other public forums available to its users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when using these and avoid posting any personal information.

**_How we protect your information_**

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites.

**_How long we keep your information_**

We retain personal data for as long as you have an account with us in order to meet our contractual obligations to you and for six years after that to identify any issues and resolve any legal proceedings. We may also retain aggregate information beyond this time for research purposes and to help us develop and improve our services. You cannot be identified from aggregate information retained or used for these purposes.

**_Your rights_**

You have the right under certain circumstances:

  * to be provided with a copy of your personal data held by us;
  * to request the rectification or erasure of your personal data held by us;
  * to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data (while we verify or investigate your concerns with this information, for example);
  * to object to the further processing of your personal data, including the right to object to marketing (as mentioned in 'Our promotional updates and communications' section above);
  * to request that your provided personal data be moved to a third party.

Your right to withdraw consent:

Where the processing of your personal information by us is based on consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent without detriment at any time by contacting us. You can also change your marketing preferences at any time as described in 'Our promotional updates and communications' section;

You can also exercise the rights listed above at any time by contacting us at info@gatestoneinstitute.org.

If your request or concern is not satisfactorily resolved by us, you may approach your local data protection authority, (see <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.html> ). The **_Information Commissioner_** is the supervisory authority in the UK and can provide further information about your rights and our obligations in relation to your personal data, as well as deal with any complaints that you have about our processing of your personal data.

**_Changes to this policy_**

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in future will be posted on this page and, in relation to substantive changes, will be notified to you by e-mail. This policy was last updated on June 27, 2018.

**_Contact Us_**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to: [info@gatestoneinstitute.org](mailto:info@gatestoneinstitute.org)

Get Free Exclusive Gatestone Content: 

**TRAILER: BDS -- Beyond Deception Strategy  
A Pierre Rehov Film**
